Disorientation. Hallucinations. Hysteria. Sleep is survival.
Awake is a drama, science fiction, thriller film directed by Mark Raso.
After a sudden global event wipes out all electronics and takes away
humankind’s ability to sleep, chaos quickly begins to consume the world.
Only Jill, an ex-soldier with a troubled past, may hold the
key to a cure in the form of her own daughter.
The question is, can Jill safely deliver her daughter and save
the world before she herself loses her mind.
Jill, played by Gina Rodriguez.
Matilda, played by Ariana Greenblatt.
Noah, played by Lucius Hoyos.
Dodge, played by Shamier Anderson.
Dr. Murphy, played by Jennifer Jason Leigh.
Brian, played by Finn Jones.
Awake is a 2021 American apocalyptic science fiction thriller film, directed by
Mark Raso, from a screenplay he wrote alongside Joseph Raso.
It stars Gina Rodriguez, Jennifer Jason Leigh, Barry Pepper, Finn Jones, Shamier Anderson,
Ariana Greenblatt, Frances Fisher, Elias Edraki, Lucius Hoyos and Gil Bellows.
Rodriguez plays Jill (Rodriguez) who discovers her daughter (Greenblatt) may be immune to a disorder causing mass
chronic sleep deprivation and attempts to bring her daughter to a laboratory to help develop a cure.
The film was released by Netflix on June 9, 2021, and received generally negative reviews
from film critics who criticized the derivative plot and lack of tension.
However, it reached number one worldwide on the platform when it was released.
The film explores themes of end of the world, apocalypse, sleep deprivation.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.